Guide to the Sterling McMurrin audio collection 1960-1965
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
Sterling McMurrin audio collection
1960-1965
University of Utah Libraries, Special Collections Audio Visual Archives Special Collections 295 South 1500 East Salt Lake City, Utah 84112-0860 (801) 581-8864
A0003
McMurrin, Sterling M.
32 reel-to-reel audiotapes
The Sterling McMurrin audio collection (1960-1965) includes audio recordings of speeches and recorded depositions, including scholarship on the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and the testimony of Dr. McMurrin and other members of a University of Utah committee appointed to investigate charges of misrepresentation to obtain University funds and plagiarism in a doctoral thesis brought against a Mr. Sinha. McMurrin was a nationally recognized educator, administrator, and philosopher at the University of Utah.
Biographical Note
Dr. Sterling M. McMurrin (1914-1996), was a nationally recognized educator, administrator, and philosopher. He was a Professor of Philosophy and History at the University of Utah in 1948; Academic Vice President, 1960-1961; Provost, 1965-1966; and Dean of Graduate School, University of Utah, 1966-1979. Dr. McMurrin also held many National positions as well, including United States Commissioner of Education, 1961-1962; and Chairman of the Commission on Instructional Technology, 1968-1970.
The Sterling M. McMurrin audio collection includes speeches and recorded depositions between 1960-1965. Some tapes detail the testimony of Dr. McMurrin and other members of a University of Utah committee appointed by then University President Dr. James C. Fletcher; this was related to the appeal of one Mr. Sinha, who was studying for a doctorate degree in political science. The charges brought against Mr. Sinha included misrepresentation to obtain University funds, as well as for plagiarism in his doctoral thesis.
The other tapes in the collection deal with Dr. McMurrin's speeches on the philosophy of Mormonism, given from 1960-1965.
The collection is arranged chronologically and by subject.
Materials must be used on-site; no use of original material, access copies will be made available for viewing. Five business days advanced notice required. Access to parts of this collection may be restricted under provisions of state or federal law, condition of the material, or by donor. Some material in this collection is restricted and may only be used with special permission from the curator of the Special Collections Department.
See also the Dr. Sterling Moss McMurrin Photograph collection (P0433) and Manuscripts collection (Ms 32)
Mormon Church; Educators--Utah; Philosophy, American--20th century; Mormonism (Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints); Colleges and Universities; sound recordings
- University lectures and addresses, 1960-1965 (Box 1)
  - Philosophy of Mormonism speech, 1960 March 7; reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 1)
    Speech dating from March 07, 1960 by Dr.Sterling M. McMurrin: "The Mormon Doctrine and the Negro."
  - Dr. McMurrin: The Philosophy of Mormonism, 1965; reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 2)
    1965 Speech by Dr. Sterling M. McMurrin: "The Philosophy of Mormonism".
  - The Philosophy of Mormonism, 1965; reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 3)
    1965 Speech by Dr. Sterling M. McMurrin: "The Philosophy of Mormonism:(The Concept of Time)".
  - The Philosophy of Mormonism., 1960-1965; reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 4)
    Speech by Dr.Sterling M. McMurrin: "The Philosophy of Mormonism".
  - The Philosophy of Mormonism, 1960-1965; reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 5)
    Speech by Dr. Sterling M. McMurrin: "The Philosophy of Mormonism".
  - Sterling McMurrin: Address to Staff, 1962 September 05; reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 6)
    1962 staff address by Dr. Sterling M. McMurrin.
  - Sterling McMurrin: Closing Address to OE Staff, 1962 September 05; reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 7)
    OE Staff address delivered by Dr. Sterling M. McMurrin, Sept. 1962.
  - Dr. McMurrin: Unidentified subject of speech, 1960-1965; reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 8)
    Dr.Sterling M. McMurrin: Unidentified subject of speech.
- University committee testimony in Sinha case, 1965 (Box 2)
  Access to recorded testimony in the case of Mr. Sinha is restricted and may only be granted by the curator of Special Collections.
  - Recorded Testimony of Dr. McMurrin, 1965; reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 61-64)
    Recorded testimony of Dr. McMurrin in a University of Utah appeal committee for a Mr. Sinha.
  - Dr. McMurrin and Dr. Mostofi recorded testimony, 1965; reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 65)
    Testimony of Dr. McMurrin and Dr. Mostofi in a 1965 University of Utah appeal committee for a Mr. Sinha.
  - Dr. Mostofi recorded testimony, 1965; reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 66-67)
    Recorded testimony of Dr. Mostofi in a University of Utah appeal committee for a Mr. Sinha.
  - Recorded testimony of Dr. Mostofi and Dr. Dalgliesh, 1965; reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 68)
    Recorded testimony of Dr. Mostofi and Dr. Dalgliesh in a University of Utah appeal committee for a Mr. Sinha.
  - Recorded testimony of Dr Dalgliesh and Mr. Sinha, 1965; reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 69)
    Recorded testimony of Dr Dalgliesh and Mr. Sinha in a 1965 University of Utah appeal committee regarding alleged misconduct by Mr. Sinha.
  - Recorded testimony of Mr. Sinha and Dr. McMurrin, 1965; reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 70)
    Recorded testimony of Mr. Sinha and Dr. McMurrin in a 1965 University of Utah appeal committee regarding alleged misconduct by Mr. Sinha.
  - Recorded testimony of Mr. Sinha, Mrs. Wood, and Dr. Callis, 1965; reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 71)
    Recorded testimony of a Mr. Sinha, Mrs. Wood, and Dr. Callis in a 1965 University of Utah appeal committee regarding alleged misconduct by Mr. Sinha.
  - Recorded Testimony of Dr. Callis, 1965; reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 72)
    Recorded testimony of Dr. Callis in a 1965 University of Utah appeal committee regarding alleged misconduct by a Mr. Sinha.
  - Recorded testimony of Dr. Callis, Dr. Jarvis, Dr. Mostofi, 1965; reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 73)
    Recorded testimony of Dr. Callis, Dr. Jarvis, Dr. Mostofi in a 1965 University of Utah appeal committee regarding alleged misconduct by a Mr. Sinha.
  - Recorded testimony of Dr. Mostofi, 1965; reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 74-77)
    Recorded testimony of Dr. Mostofi in a 1965 University of Utah appeal committee regarding alleged misconduct by a Mr. Sinha.
  - Recorded Testimony of Dr. Mostofi, Dr. Weaver, and Dr. Johnson, 1965; reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 78)
    Recorded Testimony of Dr. Mostofi, Dr. Weaver, and Dr. Johnson in a 1965 University of Utah appeal committee regarding alleged misconduct by a Mr. Sinha.
  - Recorded Testimony of Mr. Sinha, 1965; reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 79-84)
    Recorded testimony of Mr. Sinha in a 1965 University of Utah appeal committee hearing regarding his own alleged misconduct.
    reel-to-reel audiotape